# **NEHA CHANDEL**

CONSERVATION ARCHITECT AND URBAN SKETCHER

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Phone - 6006263807

Email - ar.neha.chandel@gmail.com

**CEPT Portfolio Link -**

https://portfolio.cept.ac.in/student/nehasingh-chandel-pg190598

City - Ahmedabad, Gujarat

**Social link** - linkedin.com/nehachandel

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Graduated with Masters in Architectural Conservation and Regeneration (M. Arch) from CEPT University, Ahmedabad after 3 years of practice in Pune.

My interest lies in working on heritage structures - modification, extension, repair, renovation, adaptive reuse and regeneration in its diverse contexts. As an Urban Sketcher, I have an inbuilt process of curating, framing and archiving visual and oral narratives related to a site which is crucial to existing structures. Being a team-player, always open to work, share and collaborate with experts from different bodies of architecture.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Centre for Environment Planning and Technology (CEPT)

Masters in Architectural Conservation and Urban Regeneration (M. Arch) 2019-2021

- Traditional Building Material Study & Lab tests, Documentation of Built Heritage and its Attributes (Link to Short Film)
- Proposed Architectural Conservation of Colonial General Post Office, Ahmedabad
- SEM 3: (Thesis under Ar. Gurmeet Rai)
   Codifying Embedded Knowledge in
   Earthquake Responsive Traditional
   Buildings of Kashmir Valley

SEM 4: Urban Regeneration of Water Systems of Jammu: Case of Ranbir Canal

## 2011-2016 - B. Arch, Pune University

Minerva College of Architecture 2011-2016

Dissertation: How Multi-functional

Can a Space Be?

Thesis: Modulation Hub & its Prototype Module for Disaster Victims of Jammu & Kashmir

#### **INTERNSHIP - 1 Year 1 Month**

Conservation Architects, World Monument Fund (WMF) & Getty Conservation Institute (GCI)

Ar. Bhawna Dandona, Gurgaon

Conservation Intern Aug – Sept 2021

 Digitizing, Documenting and Drafting Comprehensive Conservation Management Plan for Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Stadium, Ahmedabad

#### **ACS Consultants**

Lonavala, Pune July 2021

Design Intern

- Designed Lake-side Zostel at Lonavala
- Designed and modelled lake side Bungalow

#### Dharohar & Kalakriti

Ar. Sangeeta Bais, Delhi May-June 2020

- Summer Intern (Masters)
- Trained in traditional material and repair in built heritage with experts
- Critically analyzed Metal and Concrete restoration in 20<sup>th</sup> Century Modern Heritage - Capitol Complex Chandigarh

#### Vastu Vision & Associates

Ar. Nachiket Patil, Pune Sep-Dec 2015

Professional Practice Intern (Bachelors)

 Modelled and represented individual houses, Apartment housing and commercial structures for the rural areas of Khed through working drawings, corporation drawings, designing and 3-D views

#### **B.V.Sharma & Associates**

Ar. B.V. Sharma, Jammu May-Aug 2015

Professional Practice Intern (Bachelors)

 Conceptualized Public Buildings, Residential and Interior Projects

#### **MEMBERSHIPS**

COA CA/2016/7709
ICOMOS ASC/2021/255

### **WORK EXPERIENCE - 3 years**

Kimaya Ar. Anjali & Kiran Kalamdani Chinchwad, Pune April 2017 - 2019 Junior Architect

- Designed New Extension for Central Building Pune, Teakwood Stairway for Morgaon Ganpati Mandir and Smart City Park in Baner
- Conserved/Restored a site of Colonial Bungalows in Pune
- Analyzed Structural Reports, Construction
   Bill Certifications and Tenders

# Suraj Kocheta & Associates, Pune

Ar. Nachiket Patil, Pune 2016-2017

**Assistant Architect** 

- Visualized and represented projects through Working Drawings, Furniture Layouts
- Planned Site Upgradation of ISCKON Temple Complex at Akurdi
- Built physical models for Exhibition Display at TCS Hinjewadi

#### **SKILLS**

Sketching, Documentation, Condition Mapping, Estimation, Bill Certification, Intervention Design, Site Supervision, Infographic Design, Photogrammetry, 3-D Model, Analysis & BIM, Film & Videography, Research, Presentation & Report, New Building Design